ALES Labor Education Records 5225 E
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ALES Labor Education Records
1913-1961
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
American Labor Education Service (ALES)
5225 E
6 cubic feet
6 linear ft.
Records (documents).
8209452
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
A. Holland-Loucks, August 02, 2011
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 21, 2017
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5225: ALES Records 5225 C: ALES Course Materials 5225 I: ALES International Labor Records 5225 L: ALES Labor Plays 5225 S: ALES Scrapbooks 5225 MB: ALES Pearl L. Willen Memorial Memorabilia
American Labor Education Service (ALES)
8209452
- "Internasjonale Arbeidskonference 1941 Den Borske Delegasjons rapport (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Norwegian, English
- Austria Folder #1, 1950-1956 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Austrian-German, English
- Austria Folder #2, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Austrian Labor News, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Booklets, 1951-1954 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Austrian German, English
- Booklets #2, 1947-1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Austria Folder #3, 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Die Asterreichische Volkshochschule, 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Die Asterreichische Volkshochschule, 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Austria Folder #4, 1957-1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Austria Folder #6, 1957-1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Austrian German
- Belgium, 1922-1934 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- The Highway, 1932-1935 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Various Booklets, Annual Reports, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Various Booklets, Annual Reports Folder #2, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- "Economics" Reading and Other Booklets, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- "The Plebs", 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Booklets, 1944-1950 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- England, 1928-1941 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Danish School Work, 1933-1935 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Danish, English
- Danish School Work #2, 1931-1932 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Denmark- Danish Consul, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- "The Plebs", 1930-1936 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Booklets - Y.M.C.A., Colleges, 1930-1936 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Educational Booklets, 1928-1934 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- England - Residential Colleges for Working Women, 1934-1939 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Booklets - Colleges, Labor Unions, 1934-1939 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- The University of Sheffield, 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Education - England, University of London, 1921-1934 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous Booklets, 1926-1935 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Booklets on Adult Education, 1929-1933 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Reports - Education in England, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- "Dag-Nachrichten" German News Folder #1, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  German
- "Dag-Nachrichten" German News Folder #2, 1956-1960 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- "Dag-Nachrichten" German News folder #3, 1956-1960 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- "Cooperation and Achievements" Finnish Documents, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Finnish, English
- German Booklets; Otto Stammer, 1957-1960 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- "Arbeit Und Leben" German Essays, 1944-1959 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- "Europa Archiv", 1956 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- "Frauenstimme", 1956 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- German Booklets, News - 1950s, 1955-1957 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- News from Germany, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- German Documents, 1956-1960 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Norway, 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Norway #2, 1957-1959 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Russian Newspapers, Documents, 1928-1938 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  Russian, English
- Norway #3, 1933-1957 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Adult Education- German Universities, 1926-1940 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  German, English
- Sweden Booklets, 1927-1934 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Swedish
- Swedish Publications, 1931-1934 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- The Journal of Electircal Workers and Operators, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Swedish Books, 1927-1932 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Swedish Newsletters, 1936-1959 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- "Fonstret", 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Misc.- Sweden Folder #1, 1932-1951 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Misc. - Sweden Folder #2, 1933-1935 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Misc. - Sweden Folder #3, 1947-1948 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- "Brunnsviks; Minnesskrift", 1931 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Misc.- Sweden Folder #4, 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- "Kurser", 1932-1934 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- "Cooperative Union" Swedish, 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Misc. - Sweden Folder #5, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  Swedish, English
- Swedish News Articles, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- "ABF" Sweden, 1938-1940 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- "ABT" Folder #2, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- "ABF" Folder #3, 1932-1933 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Sweden - Letters, Booklets, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Sweden, Engilsh
- The New York Times and Swedish Newspaper, 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Swedish Newspapers, 1930-1932 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Swedish Documents, 1930-1933 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Swedish Newspapers and Letters, 1933-1935 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Statistics - Sweden Social Board Folder #2, 1933-1935 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Statistics - Sweden Social Board Folder #2, 1916-1933 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Switzerland - Documents, Newsletters, Annual Reports, 1930-1959 (Box 6, Folder 11)